//Chapter 8
{"answers":["!=","<>","<=","=","None of the above"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which of the following relational operators would be used in a non-equijoin?","category":6},
{"answers":["INNER","JOIN","ON","FROM","SELECT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />SELECT *<br />FROM my_table_1 one<br />INNER JOIN my_table_2 two<br />ON one.my_data = two.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />Which of the following keywords in the above statement can be removed?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","NULL","Execution fails","No row selected"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />SELECT my_data<br />FROM my_table_1<br />JOIN my_table_2<br />USING (my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","NULL","No row selected","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER, my_data2 NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER, my_data2 NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1, 1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1, 2);<br /><br />SELECT my_data2<br />FROM my_table_1<br />JOIN my_table_2<br />USING (my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["They rename a table in the data dictionary","They are equivalent to a SYNONYM","Exist only in the scope of the immediate query","Can be used to clarify table references in a join","They are database objects"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,true,false],"question":"Which of the following is true about table aliases?","category":6},
{"answers":["Equijoin","Inner join","Outer join","Nonequijoin","Natural join"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />SELECT my_data<br />FROM my_table_1<br />JOIN my_table_2<br />USING (my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What kind of join is this?","category":6},
{"answers":["INNER","OUTER","NATURAL","LEFT","CROSS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"_______ joins connect rows only if they are matched in all joined tables.","category":6},
{"answers":["OUTER","INNER","NATURAL","LEFT","CROSS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"_______ joins can connect rows as long as they exist in at least one of the joined tables.","category":6},
{"answers":["Equijoin","Non-equijoin","Cartesian join"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"An _________ is a join that connects only on exact data matching.","category":6},
{"answers":["Equijoin","Non-equijoin","Cartesian join"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"An _________ is a join that connects on relational operators rather than exact data matching.","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />INNER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />LEFT JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />LEFT OUTER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />RIGHT JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","3"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />RIGHT JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","3"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />RIGHT JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","0","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a,<br />my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />FULL OUTER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />FULL OUTER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />FULL OUTER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data = b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />JOIN my_table_2 b<br />USING(my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />JOIN my_table_2 b<br />USING(a.my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_other_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />JOIN my_table_2 b<br />USING(my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data < b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />FULL OUTER JOIN my_table_2 b<br />ON a.my_data < b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"<br />Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (3);<br /><br />SELECT *<br />FROM my_table a<br />JOIN my_table b<br />ON a.my_data < b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["5","6","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (3);<br /><br />SELECT *<br />FROM my_table a<br />FULL OUTER JOIN my_table <br />ON a.my_data < b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a,<br />my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data(+);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a,<br />my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data(+) < b.my_data;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["Primary key constraints are necessary on joined tables","Foreign key constraints are necessary on joined tables","Columns from any of the joined tables can be selected"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true],"question":"Which of the following is true about joins?","category":6},
{"answers":["INNER","OUTER","CROSS","NATURAL","SELF"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"A _________ join is used to automatically connect equivalently spelled columns among all joined tables.","category":6},
{"answers":["INNER joins","OUTER joins"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"NATURAL joins are _________ by default.","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"<br />Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data_1 NUMBER, my_data_2 NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data_1 NUMBER, my_other_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1, 1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2, 2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1, 1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4, 1);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />NATURAL JOIN my_table_2 b;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},
{"answers":["1","2","4","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data_1 NUMBER, my_data_2 NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data_1 NUMBER, my_other_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1, 1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2, 2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1, 1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4, 1);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />NATURAL LEFT JOIN my_table_2 b;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":6},


//Chapter 9

{"answers":["Subquery","Query","View","Selector","Proceudre"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"A _______ is a SELECT statement that exists within a larger SQL statement.","category":7},
{"answers":["Single-row","Multiple-row","Multiple-column","Correlated","Scalar"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"A _______ subquery returns one row of data only, regardless of the number of columns.","category":7},
{"answers":["Single-row","Multiple-row","Multiple-column","Correlated","Scalar"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"A _______ subquery returns one or more rows of data, regardless of the number of columns.","category":7},
{"answers":["Single-row","Multiple-row","Multiple-column","Correlated","Scalar"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"A _______ subquery returns more than one column worth of data, regardless of the number of rows.","category":7},
{"answers":["Single-row","Multiple-row","Multiple-column","Correlated","Scalar"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"A _______ subquery references tables or aliases from the parent query.","category":7},
{"answers":["Single-row","Multiple-row","Multiple-column","Correlated","Scalar"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"A _______ subquery returns only one row consisting of a single column.","category":7},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","4","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE EXISTS <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","4","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE EXISTS <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","4","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE EXISTS <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","4","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false,false],"question":"<br />Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (4);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE NOT EXISTS <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","4","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (2);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE NOT EXISTS <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2 b<br />WHERE a.my_data = b.my_data);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["WITH","RENAME","RANK","GROUP BY","DEFINE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The ______ clause is used to assign a name to a subquery block for later reference in a SELECT statement.","category":7},
{"answers":["1","NULL","3","4","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />WITH calc_1 AS<br />(SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL),<br />calc_2 AS<br />(SELECT 3 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT a.val + b.val<br />FROM calc_1 a, calc_2 b;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","NULL","3","4","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />WITH calc_1 AS<br />(SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL),<br />calc_2 AS<br />(SELECT 3 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT calc_1.val + calc_2.val;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","NULL","3","4","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />WITH calc_1 AS<br />(SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL),<br />calc_2 AS<br />(SELECT 3 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT calc_1.val + calc_2.val<br />FROM dual;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","No rows selected","3","2","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (2);<br /><br />SELECT my_data from <br />my_table <br />WHERE my_data = (<br />WITH calc_1 AS<br />(SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT a.val as my_data<br />FROM calc_1 a);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","No rows selected","3","2","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (2);<br /><br />SELECT my_data from <br />my_table <br />WHERE NOT EXISTS (<br />WITH calc_1 AS<br />(SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT a.val as my_data<br />FROM calc_1 a<br />WHERE my_table.my_data = a.val);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","4","3","2","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (2);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE a.my_data = <br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2 b);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["1","No rows returned","3","2","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (2);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (3);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (2);<br /><br />SELECT MIN(a.my_data)<br />FROM my_table_1 a<br />WHERE a.my_data > ALL (SELECT * from my_table_2);<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":7},
{"answers":["ALL","SOME","IN","NOT","ANY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _____ comparison condition returns true if a relational operator returns true for EVERY row returned by a multi-row subquery.","category":7},
{"answers":["ALL","SOME","IN","NOT","ANY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,true],"question":"The _____ comparison condition returns true if a relational operator returns true for at least one row returned by a multi-row subquery.","category":7},
{"answers":["ALL","SOME","IN","NOT","ANY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"The _____ comparison condition returns true if the subject value equals at least one row returned by a multi-row subquery.","category":7},

//Chapter 10

{"answers":["1","2","3","4","5"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />1. CREATE TABLE my_table <br />2. (my_data NUMBER);<br />3. CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />4. SELECT my_data + 1<br />5. FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />At what line number is the syntax error?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","2","0","3","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data + 1<br />FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_view;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","2","0","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data + 1 as my_data<br />FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_view;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","2","0","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_view VALUES (1);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_view;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","2","0","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_view VALUES (1);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","0","2","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER NOT NULL);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_view VALUES (NULL);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_view;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["1","0","2","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT DISTINCT my_data FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_view VALUES (1);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["The DML operation would violate a constraint on the base table","The VIEW's SELECT query uses DISTINCT","The VIEW's SELECT query uses GROUP BY","The VIEW's SELECT references more than one table","The VIEW's SELECT query uses ORDER BY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,true,true,false],"question":"In which of the following situations will you be prevented from perfroming DML operations on a VIEW?","category":13},
{"answers":["5","0","NULL","No rows returned","Execution fails"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE VIEW my_view AS<br />SELECT my_data,<br />my_data + 1 as calc FROM my_table;<br />INSERT INTO my_view (my_data) VALUES (5);<br />SELECT MAX(my_data) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["Inline View","View","Table alias","Synonym"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false],"question":"A ___________ is a subquery that replaces a table reference in the FROM clause of a SELECT statement.","category":13},
{"answers":["COMPILE","RECOMPILE","CREATE OR REPLACE","REBUILD","VALIDATE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The ALTER VIEW .... ______; statement is used to restore an invalid VIEW to a valid state.","category":13},
{"answers":["They are not fetched by a SELECT * statement","They are not fetched when named in a select list","When named in a VIEW object's select statement, they are fetched by SELECT * on that view.","They can never be set to VISIBLE<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,true,false],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding INVISIBLE columns?","category":13},
{"answers":["INCREMENT BY","MAXVALUE","ADD","START WITH","CYCLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The __________ option when creating a SEQUENCE object indicates what number the SEQUENCE increments by.","category":13},
{"answers":["INCREMENT BY","MAXVALUE","ADD","START WITH","CYCLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The __________ option when creating a SEQUENCE object indicates the first number of the sequence.","category":13},
{"answers":["INCREMENT","SET CYCLICAL","NOCYCLE","SET REPEAT","CYCLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The __________ option when creating a SEQUENCE object indicates that the counter should \"rollover\" the MINVALUE when MAXVALUE is reached.","category":13},
{"answers":["5","6","4","-1","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE SEQUENCE my_seq<br />MAXVALUE 10<br />START WITH 5<br />INCREMENT BY -1;<br />SELECT my_seq.nextval FROM DUAL;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["5","6","4","-1","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE SEQUENCE my_seq<br />MAXVALUE 10<br />START WITH 5<br />INCREMENT BY -1;<br />SELECT my_seq.currval FROM DUAL;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["5","6","4","-1","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE SEQUENCE my_seq<br />MAXVALUE 10<br />START WITH 5<br />INCREMENT BY -1;<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (my_seq.nextval);<br />SELECT my_seq.nextval FROM DUAL;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["5","6","4","-1","Execution fails<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE SEQUENCE my_seq<br />MAXVALUE 10<br />START WITH 5<br />INCREMENT BY -1;<br />INSERT INTO my_table VALUES (my_seq.nextval);<br />SELECT my_seq.currval FROM DUAL;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":13},
{"answers":["They are database objects.","Reference a single column in a composite index does not invoke the index.","They are primarily used to increase query performance.","They are recorded in the data dictionary.","You can create multiple visible indexes on the same column set."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,true,true,false],"question":"Which of the following is true about indexes?","category":13},
{"answers":["PRIMARY KEY","UNIQUE","FOREIGN KEY","CHECK","NOT NULL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,false,false,false],"question":"When you create a _________ constraint, an INDEX is automatically created.","category":13},
{"answers":["The Oracle query optimizer will not consider it","It cannot be dropped","Its name can be used by another index","Further DML modifications to the base table will not update it","You can create another index for the same column set."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"When an index is set to INVISIBLE...","category":13},
{"answers":["Yes, it completes successfully.","No, it fails on line 1.","No, it fails on line 2.","No, it fails on line 3."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true],"question":"<br />Does the following code execute successfully?<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />1. CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />2. CREATE INDEX my_idx_1 ON my_table(my_data) INVISIBLE;<br />3. CREATE INDEX my_idx_2 ON my_table(my_data) VISIBLE;<br /></div><br /><br />","category":13},
{"answers":["Can recover dropped tables.","Restores data from the recycle bin.","Can recover dropped columns.","Can recover tables that have been PURGED.<br />","Can recover dropped indexes."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,true,false,false],"question":"The FLASHBACK TABLE command...","category":13},
{"answers":["PURGE","FLASHBACK","TRUNCATE","EMPTY","DROP"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _____ command is used to permenantly delete data from the recycle bin.","category":13},
{"answers":["True","False"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"True or False: FLASHBACK recovers the names of all database objects it restores.","category":13},
{"answers":["A TIMESTAMP","A RESTORE POINT","A SAVEPOINT","A system change number (SCN)"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,false,true],"question":"FLASHBACK TABLE can restore a table from...","category":13},
{"answers":["It can restore data from tables which have been structurally altered.","It invokes an implicit COMMIT.","It restores all names to recovered objects.","It requires ROW MOVEMENT to be enabled in most cases."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,true],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding FLASHBACK?","category":13},
{"answers":["They are database objects.","They are not owned by users but are rather in the scope of the entire database.","They can be used as a time reference to FLASHBACK a table.","They cannot be dropped.<br />"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,true,false],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding RESTORE POINTS?","category":13}

//Chapter 11

{"answers":["UNION","UNION ALL","INTERSECT","MINUS","LEFT JOIN"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The ______ set operator combines two row sets and removes all duplicates.","category":8},
{"answers":["UNION","UNION ALL","INTERSECT","MINUS","WITH"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The ______ set operator combines two row sets and keeps all duplicates.","category":8},
{"answers":["UNION","UNION ALL","INTERSECT","MINUS","WITH"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"The ______ set operator includes only rows which are present in both sets.","category":8},
{"answers":["UNION","UNION ALL","INTERSECT","MINUS","WITH"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The ______ set operator removes all rows from the first set which exist in the second set.","category":8},
{"answers":["The number of entries in the select lists must be equivalent.","The data types of the entries in the select lists do not matter.","Large data types such as BLOB and CLOB can be used.","The ORDER BY clause cannot be used until the end of all set operations.","Set operators have equal precedence and will execute in the order which they appear."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,true,true],"question":"Which of the following is true about using set operators in a SELECT statement?","category":8},
{"answers":["1","0","2","4","3"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL statement:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM<br />((SELECT * FROM my_table_1)<br />INTERSECT<br />(SELECT * FROM my_table_2));<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":8},
{"answers":["MINUS","UNION","UNION ALL","INTERSECT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false],"question":"Which set operator would produce different outputs if you swapped the SELECT statements which proceed and follow it?","category":8}


//Chapter 12

{"answers":["USER_TABLES","ALL_TABLES","DBA_TABLES","USER_ALL_TAB","DBA_TABS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all tables owned by the current user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_TABLES","ALL_TABLES","DBA_TABLES","USER_ALL_TAB","DBA_TABS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all tables visible to the current user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_TABLES","ALL_TABLES","DBA_TABLES","USER_ALL_TAB","DBA_TABS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all tables in the database.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_CATALOG","USER_COL_PRIVS","USER_CONSTRAINTS","USER_CONS_COLUMNS","USER_DEPENDENCIES"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all tables, views, synonyms and sequences owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_ERRORS","USER_COL_PRIVS","USER_CONSTRAINTS","USER_CONS_COLUMNS","USER_DEPENDENCIES"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all grants on columns of tables owned by USER.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_CONSTRAINTS","USER_CONS_COLUMNS","USER_DEPENDENCIES","USER_ERRORS","USER_INDEXES"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all constraints owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_CONS_COLUMNS","USER_DEPENDENCIES","USER_ERRORS","USER_INDEXES","USER_IND_COLUMNS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all columns used in constraints, owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_DEPENDENCIES","USER_ERRORS","USER_INDEXES","USER_IND_COLUMNS","USER_OBJECTS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all dependencies to and from a user's objects.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_DEPENDENCIES","USER_ERRORS","USER_INDEXES","USER_IND_COLUMNS","USER_OBJECTS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all current errors on stored objects owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_INDEXES","USER_IND_COLUMNS","USER_OBJECTS","USER_SEQUENCES","USER_SYNONYMS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all indexes owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_IND_COLUMNS","USER_OBJECTS","USER_SEQUENCES","USER_SYNONYMS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all columns used in indexes owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_IND_COLUMNS","USER_OBJECTS","USER_SEQUENCES","USER_CATALOG","USER_TAB_COLUMNS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all objects owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_SEQUENCES","USER_SYNONYMS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","USER_VIEWS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all sequences owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_PRIV_SYNONYMS","USER_SYNONYMS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","USER_VIEWS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all private synonyms owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_SEQUENCES","USER_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","USER_VIEWS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all columns in user's tables and views.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_ROLES","USER_GRANTS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","USER_VIEWS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all grants on objects owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["USER_ROLES","USER_SCRIPTS","USER_TAB_COLUMNS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","USER_VIEWS"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"The _________ data dictionary table contains information regarding all views owned by the user.","category":11},
{"answers":["$V","DBA","USER","ALL","CACHE$$"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Data dictionary tables beginning with ____ or similar are dynamic performance views which track database activity in real time.","category":11},
{"answers":["$V","DBA","USER","ALL","CACHE$$"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Data dictionary tables beginning with ____ refer to objects in scope of the entire database.","category":11},
{"answers":["$V","DBA","USER","ALL","CACHE$$"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Data dictionary tables beginning with ____ refer to objects in scope of the current user's ownership.","category":11},
{"answers":["$V","DBA","USER","ALL","CACHE$$"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Data dictionary tables beginning with ____ refer to objects in scope of the current user's privileges, regardless of owner.","category":11},
{"answers":["V$DATABASE","V$PARAMETER","V$SESSION","V$RESERVED_WORDS","V$CATALOG"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"The ________ dynamic performance view contains information regarding system parameters.","category":11},
{"answers":["V$DATABASE","V$PARAMETER","V$SESSION","V$RESERVED_WORDS","V$CATALOG"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"The ________ dynamic performance view contains information regarding each user session, including active connections and login times.","category":11}
{"answers":["V$DATABASE","V$PARAMETER","V$SESSION","V$OBJECT_USAGE","V$CATALOG"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The ________ dynamic performance view contains information regarding usage of INDEX objects.","category":11},
{"answers":["V$DATABASE","V$PARAMETER","V$SESSION","V$TIMEZONE_NAMES","V$CATALOG"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The ________ dynamic performance view contains timezone names and abbreviations.","category":11},
{"answers":["P","R","U","C","PK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"In the USER_CONSTRAINTS data dictionary view, the CONSTRAINT_TYPE which maps to PRIMARY KEY IS...","category":11},
{"answers":["P","R","U","C","PK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"In the USER_CONSTRAINTS data dictionary view, the CONSTRAINT_TYPE which maps to FOREIGN KEY IS...","category":11},
{"answers":["P","R","U","C","PK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"In the USER_CONSTRAINTS data dictionary view, the CONSTRAINT_TYPE which maps to UNQIUE IS...","category":11},
{"answers":["P","R","U","C","PK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"In the USER_CONSTRAINTS data dictionary view, the CONSTRAINT_TYPE which maps to CHECK IS...","category":11},
{"answers":["P","R","U","C","NN"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"In the USER_CONSTRAINTS data dictionary view, the CONSTRAINT_TYPE which maps to NOT NULL IS...","category":11},


//Chapter 13

{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    WHEN val = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val <= 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val >= 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL;<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT FIRST<br />    WHEN val = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val <= 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val >= 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL;<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT FIRST<br />    WHEN val = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val != 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    ELSE<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL;<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    WHEN val = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN val != 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    ELSE<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL;<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    WHEN 1 = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    WHEN (2 - 1) = 1 THEN<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br /><br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1);<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"<br />Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (1)<br />SELECT NULL as nonsense FROM DUAL;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14}
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table<br />    INTO my_table<br />    INTO my_table<br />SELECT 1 as data FROM DUAL;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table<br />SELECT 1 as data FROM DUAL;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT<br />    INTO my_table<br />    INTO my_table<br />SELECT 1 as data FROM DUAL;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table(calc_1.val)<br />    INTO my_table(calc_2.val)<br />WITH <br />calc_1 AS (SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL),<br />calc_2 AS (SELECT 2 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT * <br />FROM calc_1, calc_2;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br /><br />INSERT ALL<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (val_1)<br />    INTO my_table VALUES (val_2)<br />WITH <br />calc_1 AS (SELECT 1 as val FROM DUAL),<br />calc_2 AS (SELECT 2 as val FROM DUAL)<br />SELECT calc_1.val as val_1, <br />calc_2.val as val_2<br />FROM calc_1, calc_2;<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />MERGE INTO my_table_1 a<br />USING my_table_2 b<br />ON (b.my_data NOT IN a.my_data)<br />WHEN NOT MATCHED THEN INSERT (my_data)<br />VALUES (b.my_data);<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table_1;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />MERGE INTO my_table_1 a<br />USING my_table_2 b<br />ON (b.my_data IN a.my_data)<br />WHEN NOT MATCHED THEN INSERT (my_data)<br />VALUES (b.my_data);<br />    <br />SELECT COUNT(*) FROM my_table_1;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},
{"answers":["0","1","2","3","Execution fails."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"<br />Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table_1 (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE TABLE my_table_2 (my_data NUMBER);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_1 VALUES (1);<br />INSERT INTO my_table_2 VALUES (1);<br /><br />MERGE INTO my_table_1 a<br />USING my_table_2 b<br />ON (b.my_data IN a.my_data)<br />WHEN MATCHED THEN UPDATE SET<br />my_data = b.my_data + 1;<br />    <br />SELECT my_data FROM my_table_1;<br /></div><br /><br />What is the result?","category":14},

//Chapter 14

{"answers":["System privilege","Object privilege","Role","User privilege","Session privilege"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"A ____________ is a privilege which allows a user to to perform a particular task in the database.","category":12},
{"answers":["System privilege","Object privilege","Role","User privilege","Session privilege"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"A ____________ is a privilege which allows a user to to perform a particular task on a particular database object.","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE SESSION","CONNECT","ACCESS DATABASE","READ ACCESS","READ ONLY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The __________ system privilege allows a user to connect to the database.","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE SYNONYM","CREATE PUBLIC SYNONYM","ALTER ANY SYNONYM","GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","SET SYNONYM PUBLIC"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The __________ system privilege allows a user to create a synonym in the PUBLIC account.","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE ANY TABLE","CREATE TABLE","CREATE TABLE GLOBAL","ALTER ANY TABLE","CREATE PUBLIC TABLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The __________ system privilege allows a user to create a TABLE in any user account.","category":12},
{"answers":["GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","GRANT PRIVILEGES","GRANT SYSTEM PRIVILEGE","GRANT PUBLIC PRIVILEGE","GRANT ANY OBJECT PRIVILEGE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The __________ system privilege allows a user to grant any system privilege to any user account in the database.","category":12},
{"answers":["GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","GRANT PRIVILEGES","GRANT SYSTEM PRIVILEGE","GRANT PUBLIC PRIVILEGE","GRANT ANY OBJECT PRIVILEGE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"The __________ system privilege allows a user to grant any object privilege that the object's owner is able to grant.","category":12},
{"answers":["WITH ADMIN OPTION","WITH GRANT OPTION","AS ADMIN","GRANT AS ADMIN","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"When a system privilege is granted with the _________ option, then the recipient also becomes able to grant that system privilege to another user.","category":12},
{"answers":["WITH ADMIN OPTION","WITH GRANT OPTION","AS ADMIN","GRANT AS ADMIN","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"When an object privilege is granted with the _________ option, then the recipient also becomes able to grant that object privilege to another user.","category":12},
{"answers":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />GRANT CREATE SESSION TO USER_1;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO USER_1 WITH ADMIN OPTION;<br />CREATE USER USER_2 IDENTIFIED BY PASS2;<br />GRANT CREATE SESSION TO USER_2;<br />CONNECT USER_1 / PASS1;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO USER_2;<br />CONNECT SYSTEM / SYSPASS;<br />REVOKE CREATE TABLE FROM USER_1;<br /></div><br /><br />Does USER_2 have the CREATE TABLE privilege?","category":12},
{"answers":["1","2","3","4","Execution completes successfully."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />1. CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />2. GRANT CREATE SESSION TO USER_1;<br />3. GRANT CREATE TABLE TO USER_1 WITH ADMIN OPTION;<br />4. REVOKE ALL PRIVILEGES FROM USER_1;<br /></div><br /><br />At what line does the error occur?","category":12},
{"answers":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />GRANT CREATE SESSION TO USER_1;<br />CREATE USER USER_2 IDENTIFIED BY PASS2;<br />GRANT CREATE SESSION TO USER_2;<br />GRANT SELECT ON my_table TO USER_1 WITH GRANT OPTION;<br />CONNECT USER_1 / PASS1;<br />GRANT SELECT ON SYSTEM.my_table TO USER_2;<br />CONNECT SYSTEM / ORA123;<br />REVOKE SELECT ON my_table FROM USER_1;<br /></div><br /><br />Does USER_2 have the SELECT ON my_table privilege?","category":12},
{"answers":["Revoking an object privilege cascades","Revoking a system privilege does not cascade","GRANTing either optionally uses the WITH ADMIN OPTION clause.","Revoking an object privilege does not require the PRIVILEGE keyword.","Revoking a system privilege does require the PRIVILEGE keyword."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,false,true,true],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding system privileges vs object privileges?","category":12},
{"answers":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE TABLE my_table (my_data NUMBER);<br />CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />GRANT SELECT ON my_table TO USER_1;<br />DROP TABLE my_table;<br /></div><br /><br />Does USER_1 have the SELECT ON my_table privilege?","category":12},
{"answers":["USER_SYS_PRIVS","DBA_SYS_PRIVS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","DBA_TAB_PRIVS","ALL_TAB_PRIVS_RECD"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"The _______ data dictionary view shows all system privileges granted to the current user.","category":12},
{"answers":["USER_SYS_PRIVS","DBA_SYS_PRIVS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","DBA_TAB_PRIVS","ALL_TAB_PRIVS_RECD"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The _______ data dictionary view shows all object privileges granted to every user in the database.","category":12},
{"answers":["USER_SYS_PRIVS","DBA_SYS_PRIVS","USER_TAB_PRIVS","SESSION_PRIVS","ALL_TAB_PRIVS_RECD"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"The _______ data dictionary view shows all privileges granted to the current user.","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE SESSION","CREATE TABLE","GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","CREATE PROCEDURE","CREATE ANY TABLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Which of the following privileges is contained in the CONNECT role?","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE SESSION","CREATE TABLE","GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","CREATE PROCEDURE","CREATE ANY TABLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,true,false],"question":"Which of the following privileges is contained in the RESOURCE role?","category":12},
{"answers":["CREATE USER","CREATE PUBLIC SYNONYM","GRANT ANY PRIVILEGE","CREATE SEQUENCE","CREATE ANY TABLE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,true,true,true,true],"question":"Which of the following privileges is contained in the DBA role?","category":12},
{"answers":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE ROLE my_role;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO my_role;<br />CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO USER_1;<br />GRANT my_role TO USER_1;<br />REVOKE CREATE TABLE FROM USER_1;<br /></div><br /><br />Does USER_1 have the CREATE TABLE privilege?","category":12},
{"answers":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"Consider the following SQL:<br /><br /><div class = \"code\"><br />CREATE ROLE my_role;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO my_role;<br />CREATE USER USER_1 IDENTIFIED BY PASS1;<br />GRANT CREATE TABLE TO USER_1;<br />GRANT my_role TO USER_1;<br />REVOKE my_role FROM USER_1;<br /></div><br /><br />Does USER_1 have the CREATE TABLE privilege?","category":12}